YEVHEN VERENYKOV

Web Developer

PERSONAL SUMMARY

As a well-experienced web developer, I always persist brand new techniques and methods with careful analysis, in order to make both clients and me achieve a big deal of success.

'The Better Service I Give. The Better Success I'll Get'

Language Skills

- English(Native)
- Chinese(Intermediate)

CONTACT DETAILS

Phone: +380 935207466

Address: Kharkiv

Email: joypender@outlook.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Web Developer

Sapphire Technology (2021-Present)

- · Spearheaded highly responsive web applications, resulting in a 30% increase in user engagement
- Pioneered adoption of progressive web app(PWA), fostering user retention and 20% additional revenue stream for clients.
- Prioritized SEO-centric web structures, leading to more than 40% increases in search engine rankings

Backend Developer

Innovate Tech (2018-2021)

- Led the development of a data caching mechanism, enhancing system performance during peak loads
- Engineered a scalable RESTful API, accommodating a 100% increase in user base without service degradation
- Identified and resolved critical performance bottlenecks

Junior Web Developer

TechLink Solutions (2015-2018)

- · Implemented pixel-perfect designs
- Spearheaded the migration of legacy code to modern frameworks
- · Actively participated in code reviews, identifying and resolving daily arising bugs

EDUCATION

University of Oregon

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, 2015 Honor: Dean's List for Academic Excellence

SKILLS

- JS Frameworks
- PHP Frameworks
- Ruby Frameworks
- Responsive Design
- · CI/CD

- Database Management
- CSS Frameworks
- WEB3
- Docker